福建·厦门
Xiamen, Fujian
快跟上我 不要走丢了
Follow me!
这条街上的好吃的 真的是太多了
There is some really nice food here!
前面有个面包店 好像有很多人在排队
I found a long line outside a bakery in front.
我们过去看一看 面包店有什么样特别的
Let’s go and have a look how is that bakery so special.
好 两块五
That’s 2.5 RMB.
叔叔 这边有多少种面包
Hello! How many kinds of buns do we sell here?
汉 堡
Burgers.
火 腿
Buns with ham inside.
炸 面 包
Fried buns.
五 指
“Five fingers”
葱 包
Green onion buns.
这个
And this
一般卖的最好的是哪种
Which is the top seller?
这个 这个 这个 这个
This, this, this, this.
那每样都给我拿一个就可以
Then I will take one of each.
各一个吗？
One of each?
对
Yes.
卖的最好的 我听说是那个炸面包
I was told that the fried buns are the most popular ones here.
对
Yes.
里面还可以加
The filling...
里面可以加菜吗
Is there filling inside?
对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah
加鸡蛋什么的都有
对
Yes, eggs, and all kinds of other ingredients.
都可以
Okay
一个这个
One of these?
对
yep
还有这个
And one of these?
对 这是
Yeah, this is...?
里面有一根火腿
There is a sausage inside.
还有一个这个 是不是
And one of these
对
Yeah
还要吗
Anything else?
还有一个不是汉堡吗
Yeah a burger.
11块5
11.5 RMB
9块 11块
(sound of uncertainty) 9……that’s 11
最终锁定：11块钱
Finalized: 11 yuan
炸面包多少钱
两块五
How much is a fried bun?
2.5RMB
外面就是摆了两个长柜子
Outside of the store we can see two cabinets.
里面就是在现做面包
Inside they are baking and frying buns at the moment.
这边的面包不仅有烤的 还有炸的
Some of the buns are baked, some are fried.
好像炸的还卖的比较好
The fried ones seem to be more popular
一天做两次
We fry buns twice a day.
上午5点钟做一次卖完 中午休息
The first time is at 5 am, then we rest in the afternoon
下午3点钟再做一次卖完就休息
The second time is at 3pm, then we rest once all the buns are sold out
叔叔 这个店开多久了
When did you start the business?
啊
Ah?
这个店开多久了
How long has this bakery been in business?
28年
28 years.
我看很多人都是一袋一袋买面包
I noticed a lot of people come and buy buns in bags. They really buy a lot.
对 对 我们开在老厦门都已经28年了
Yeah, we have been selling buns for 28 years.
我们薄利多销
Small profits but quick turnover.
薄利多销
Ahha, small profits but quick turnover.
哇 我看到你的视频了
Hey! I am a fan of yours!
对
Yeah
大哥你经常来这边来买面包吗
Do you come often to buy buns?
对
Yes
你全国各地到处跑
Yes. You really have been many places around the country!
没想到11块钱买了这么多
Didn’t expect to buy so many with just 11 RMB.
我们要去吃面包了
Let’s go and have a bite!
我的面包好像已经被压扁了
Some of the buns have been accidentally squeezed.
叔叔这边差不多有十多种面包吧
They sell like ten kinds of buns.
但是面包的价格大多数都是在两块五
The average pricing is from 2.5 yuan
到四块之间 最贵的是四块钱
To 4 yuan
一般也就是两块五
Most of them are 2.5yuan
好具有童年意义的面包
This reminds me of my childhood!
鸡腿面包
“Drumstick”!
不过他们这边卖的最好的是这种炸的面包
Their bestseller is this fried bun.
很小一个
Not too big
现在已经软了
It’s pretty soft now.
面包炸的几乎是这种褐色的
Dark golden brown.
它里面放的是鸡蛋 火腿还有葱花
The filling includes scrambled eggs, ham and chopped scallions.
没想到两块五的小面包里面
It’s amazing that there is so much inside
还有这么多的料
With this 2.5 RMB bun
第一口就咬到馅了
You will bite into the filling on you first bite
它是咸口的
It’s savory instead of sweet
有点酥脆的小面包
And it has a bit of a crunch.
面包里面加了卤蛋还有火腿肠
It has eggs and sausages inside
馅料很丰富 口感也很丰富
Gives you a rich and flavourful taste.
如果说 里面没有鸡蛋 火腿和葱花的话
If there is no filling inside
就是我们毕竟常见的这种甜口的小面包
It’s just a ordinary sweet bun.
但是它里面加了这些料之后 你会觉得
But with the filling,
吃一口 又是吃到小面包
It tastes richer in flavor
又是吃到这种带料的馅
刚才咱们吃到的是两块五一个的小面包
The one we just tried is priced 2.5 yuan
他们这边最贵的是这种
This is the most expensive one they sell
4块钱的汉堡
A 4 RMB burger.
汉堡 其实相对来说 比较常见
Burgers are more common to us
里面就是沙拉
There is salad
鸡肉条还放了两片黄瓜
Chicken strips and two slices of cucumber.
相对于四块钱的汉堡来说
I prefer the 2.5 fried bun
可能我更喜欢两块五的炸面包
than this burger
因为它的小面包的味道更突出
The fried bun was more flavorful
更深得我心
I definitely like that one better.
咱们这次主要就是尝一尝经典的炸面包
I have tried the two classic types of the buns
明天早上 等着它们吧
Let’s leave the rest for tomorrow’s breakfast!
喝杯面包
Enjoy some buns
明天早上就是吃面包 喝牛奶的生活
I’ll be drinking milk and eating buns tomorrow morning
这是叫 土笋冻
This is called Tu Sun Dong (sea worm jelly)
之前虽然说 遇到很多次的土笋冻
We’ve met with it multiple times in Xiamen
但是一直没有机会来尝它
But we never had the chance to have a try
大家说 它是一种虫子
It is said that there are worms inside
这让我觉得很好奇
I’m curious about it
今天就遇到了
Since we have met with it again
咱们就尝一尝这种
Let’s try it
看起来不怎么样
It doesn’t look all too frightening
但是听到它实质
Not as much as it sounds
觉得有点害怕的东西 是什么样的味道
What will it taste like?
它这个是土笋冻里面加了酸萝卜
What we have here are some Tu Sun Dong,
又加一些香菜还有辣椒酱
With some pickled radish, parsley, and some chili sauce
还有芥末
And mustard
它这个土笋冻 外面晶莹剔透的是地瓜粉
The translucent jelly is made of sweet potato starch
然后它里面的沙虫
And the sea worm inside
它本身是没有什么样的味道的
It’s tasteless itself
吃起来像海蜇一样
Very similar to jellyfish
全靠辣椒酱这些东西来调味
The flavor comes from the chili sauce and mustard
可是 问题来了 它为什么叫土笋冻呢
But here comes the question, why is it called Tu Sun Dong? (The word Sun in Chinese means bamboo shoots)
跟土笋长的像嘛 里面是沙虫
It’s because the sea worms looks like bamboo shoots
但是跟土笋很像 所以叫土笋冻
That’s how it gets its name
关注雪鱼探店
Subscribe
真是早上起来 把面包放在床头柜上
I left the buns on my nightstand
一起来就觉得 好想起床
I’m waken up by the fragrance.
因为饿了
I’m so hungry!